[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b91", "question": "According to their own theme song, what 1960's group was \"too busy singin' to put anybody down\"?", "answer": "The Monkees", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a7fd6c0f9723ab15cb61", "question": "What are the names of the \"see no evil, hear no evil, speak no evil\" monkey statues?", "answer": "Mizaru, Kikazaru, and Iwazaru", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c216", "question": "Which country were the 1948 Winter Olympic Games?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe76fa4eec85e375820b2ed", "question": "What is the largest city in Switzerland?", "answer": "Zurich", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c302", "question": "Which media is read from the inside out, compact discs or vinyl records?", "answer": "Compact discs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b775", "question": "What is a brigand?", "answer": "An armed bandit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a25720565ad31a57c7ab", "question": "Which brewery won the \"top beer award\" at Chicago's World Fair in 1893?", "answer": "Pabst Brewing Company", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1e3", "question": "Whose band was \"The Quarrymen\"?", "answer": "John Lennon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cf16bb53d1af658864f2", "question": "Who does an angel placed on top of the Christmas tree represent?", "answer": "Archangel Gabriel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeb7", "question": "Which American statistician founded the institute of Public Opinion in 1935?", "answer": "Gallup", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f32d01dd7bf43be5e815", "question": "What does SPF stand for?", "answer": "Sun Protection Factor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a25eee56682715b82711cd2", "question": "Which building is typically considered to be the first skyscraper?", "answer": "The Home Insurance Building", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b679", "question": "Leather is the traditional gift for which wedding anniversary?", "answer": "Third", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3b9", "question": "What do most lobsters and crayfish do with their shell after it has molted?", "answer": "Eat it", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab75", "question": "What is the capital of Mauritius?", "answer": "Port Louis", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9e9", "question": "In what Australian state would you find Port Pirie?", "answer": "South Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa71", "question": "Rioja wine comes from which country?", "answer": "Spain\u00a0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339599", "question": "Who played the roles of Harry and Sally in the movie \"When Harry Met Sally\"?", "answer": "Billy Crystal and Meg Ryan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133888d", "question": "What did the Seven Dwarfs do for a living?", "answer": "They were miners", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd37", "question": "Who scored the famous \"Hand of God\" goal in the 1986 World Cup?", "answer": "Diego Maradona", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef597d6ce05a3942286e04", "question": "How old was Miley Cyrus when she first auditioned for the role of \"Hannah Montana\"?", "answer": "11", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3e2", "question": "What is the name for a young deer?", "answer": "Fawn", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec8cb3ec223966ae8f884d", "question": "\"Bootylicious\" has become an accepted word in the Oxford Dictionary thanks to a track of the same name by which artist(s)?", "answer": "Destiny's Child", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391aa", "question": "Who played James Bond in the 1971 film \"Diamonds Are Forever\"?", "answer": "Sean Connery", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b97", "question": "Whose movie debut was opposite Humphrey Bogart in 1944's \"To Have and Have Not\"?", "answer": "Lauren Bacall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ea7", "question": "In what comic strip would you find siblings Chip, Dot, Ditto and Trixie?", "answer": "Hi and Lois", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6010cab30775fa611bce67fd", "question": "What do the Rock & Roll Hall of Fame and the Louvre have in common?", "answer": "A design by the same architect -- I.M. Pei provided the design for the entrances to both museums.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdab5230b8cce1e6fda704a", "question": "Which popular coffee drink is named after hooded monks?", "answer": "Cappuccino", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b684", "question": "What tools' variations include mill, geared head and radial arm?", "answer": "Drills'", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd81c48d0de9af39e9d4682", "question": "Who was the first U.S. president to be photographed?", "answer": "John Quincy Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c73", "question": "What Shakespearean character has the most lines?", "answer": "Hamlet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefbe1f6ce05a3942286ee8", "question": "The film \"The African Queen\" is set during what war?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071b803745b36be73039c2", "question": "Which company publishes the Chew comics series?", "answer": "Image Comics", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2d0742596a59cbdfbd37c", "question": "Who said, \"The hottest love has the coldest end\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa416fc73aa70ea0b70b0f", "question": "Which Hawaiian island is entirely privately owned?", "answer": "Ni'ihau (The island was purched by wealthy Scottish plantation owners from King Kamehameha V in 1864 for $10,000 in gold.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a17", "question": "Which composer of the \"Rite of Spring\" was still alive to see his music used in Disney's \"Fantasia\"?", "answer": "Igor Stravinsky", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b60f", "question": "What game comes packaged with a small plastic hourglass and sixteen different letter cubes?", "answer": "Boggle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff7bcbc2b316f4693fb678c", "question": "A kirby-grip is the British name for what hair accessory?", "answer": "Bobby pin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049f03cf93664eb10486b7", "question": "What US state is home to the \"One Shell Square\" skyscraper?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aee", "question": "What was Underdog's secret identity, which was also his occupation?", "answer": "Shoeshine boy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c482", "question": "Are polar bears carnivores or omnivores?", "answer": "Carnivores", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6013702d138175489539637f", "question": "In the 1990 film \"Home Alone\", which actor improvised all of his lines?", "answer": "John Candy -- He played his part as a favor to writer/producer John Hughes, and was paid scale (Screen Actors Guild minimum wage).", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133924a", "question": "What was the title of Eddie Murphy's first movie?", "answer": "48 Hrs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a30", "question": "Which Biblical figure by Michelangelo has been called \"the most recognizable statue in the history of sculpture\"?", "answer": "David", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c272", "question": "What is April's birthstone?", "answer": "Diamond", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b524e662d71a53650ff5", "question": "Born Edgar Poe, where did the middle name Allan come from?", "answer": "It was his adoptive parents' name.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c576", "question": "Which planet in our solar system is known as the Earth's twin?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab7a", "question": "What year did Mauritius gain its independence from Britain?", "answer": "1968", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae8b", "question": "What war ended in 1898 with the Battle of Manila Bay?", "answer": "Spanish-American War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e8f106d333868d34d74f", "question": "Which country's traditional name translates to \"Land of the Thunder Dragon\"?", "answer": "Bhutan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a838", "question": "What Ivy League university is located in Ithaca, NY?", "answer": "Cornell", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133904e", "question": "Which author wrote the \"Redwall\" series of novels?", "answer": "Brian Jacques", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae53", "question": "What was the name given to the first German democracy established in 1919?", "answer": "Weimar Republic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d0", "question": "Who was sent to the electric chair on the testimony of her brother David Greenglass?", "answer": "Ethel Rosenberg", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc67f6de0eb824d4052f8", "question": "Which staple food was rationed in the UK the year after the end of World War II despite having never been rationed during the war?", "answer": "Bread (Bread was rationed from 1946 to 1948 after excessive rains ruined the UK's wheat crop.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133995e", "question": "What was the name of Fred Sanford\u2019s late wife on the TV show \"Sanford & Son\"?", "answer": "Elizabeth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7b4", "question": "What was studied by Project Blue Book?", "answer": "UFOs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5f9f42a8af848b908361b86f", "question": "Who was the first full-term President of Sierra Leone?", "answer": "Siaka Stevens", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e4", "question": "Which popular musician co-wrote the song \"I'm afraid of Americans\" with David Bowie?", "answer": "Brian Eno", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8eb", "question": "What bay is actually the United States' largest tidal estuary?", "answer": "Chesapeake Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b789", "question": "What underdog knocked out Mike Tyson in Tokyo in 1990?", "answer": "Buster Douglas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015fb83fe83fe1f2a824c39", "question": "St. Patrick wrote in his Declaration that when he was 16 years what happened?", "answer": "According to his own writings, St. Patrick said he was was captured by Irish pirates when he was 16 years old.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a15d", "question": "The Golden and Silver Lions are awarded at which film festival?", "answer": "Venice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be58", "question": "What is traditionally served in a caquelon heated above a rechaud?", "answer": "Fondue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1e2", "question": "Which US president lived in Rancho del Cielo?", "answer": "Ronald Reagan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ae9323574a5ce6b56b8236", "question": "Who was the Roman goddess of youth?", "answer": "Juventas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d1e", "question": "Who composed \"5th Symphony\"?", "answer": "Ludwig van Beethoven", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ac", "question": "The troposphere, stratosphere and mesosphere all make part of the Earth's what?", "answer": "Atmosphere", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa5d", "question": "How was the country of Belize known prior to 1973?", "answer": "British Honduras", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b67d", "question": "For what game were two jokers originally included in a standard deck of playing cards?", "answer": "Euchre", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe77372eec85e375820b308", "question": "Which two oceans are connected by the Drake Passage?", "answer": "Atlantic and Pacific", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9bd", "question": "The Mario villain \"Wario\", made his first appearance in which Nintendo game?", "answer": "Super Mario Land 2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af256b3b63e5727cf5a483f", "question": "What popular toy, that is still widely used today, was invented by Arthur K. Melin in 1958?", "answer": "The Hula Hoop", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b905", "question": "The delicacy known as fois gras traditionally comes from what part of the duck or goose?", "answer": "The liver", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba60", "question": "Who spoke the first recorded message \u201cMary had a Little lamb\u201d?", "answer": "Thomas Edison", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b43", "question": "Taking advantage of a fad at the time, what song became a #1 hit for Ray Stevens in 1974?", "answer": "The Streak", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3f0", "question": "What year was Queen Elizabeth II born?", "answer": "1926", "category": "history"}, {"id": "591c382d815febcc896f927b", "question": "What is the eleventh sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Aquarius", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bd0", "question": "The group ABBA hails from what European country?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b90e", "question": "What 2 letters are often used as a written abbreviation for \"hugs and kisses\"?", "answer": "XO", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b4a6e662d71a53650fed", "question": "Which Dutch artist painted \"Girl with a Pearl Earring\"?", "answer": "Vermeer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca1c", "question": "What type of animal is a Borzoi?", "answer": "A dog", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e7e0fe83fe1f2a824bd6", "question": "What was Matthew Hopkins famous for in the 17th century?", "answer": "He was a witch-finder", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d86", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"Manhunter\" based on?", "answer": "Red Dragon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ccc", "question": "The song \"Suite: Judy Blue Eyes\" was inspired by Stephen Stills' breakup with whom?", "answer": "Judy Collins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adef", "question": "What year did the English Civil War start?", "answer": "1642", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a40", "question": "What was the first name of the American artist \"Grandma Moses\"?", "answer": "Anna", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba1d", "question": "What was unusual about Dizzy Gillespie's trumpet?", "answer": "The bell was bent upwards", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b35b", "question": "Which famous artist was shot and wounded by Valerie Solanas In 1968?", "answer": "Andy Warhol", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b625", "question": "What symbol shares a key with the number 4 on a standard computer keyboard?", "answer": "The dollar sign", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b6b", "question": "What future Oscar-winning actress played the title role on the 1960's sitcom \"Gidget\"?", "answer": "Sally Field", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0d9", "question": "What is a somnambulist?", "answer": "Sleepwalker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a34f", "question": "What is the second largest country in the World?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c77cfb324f0f7a362efd54f", "question": "\"Green Arrow: Year One\" is a limited series published by who?", "answer": "DC Comics", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ced", "question": "What is the Heart of Gold in \"The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy\"?", "answer": "A spaceship", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c39a", "question": "\"Absolute zero\" is equal to zero degrees on which temperature scale?", "answer": "Kelvin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f52", "question": "What photographer had a twenty-year relationship with late author Susan Sontag?", "answer": "Annie Leibovitz", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af24", "question": "The \"Battle of Roundway Down\" was fought during which war?", "answer": "First English Civil War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c515", "question": "What disease is the focus of oncology?", "answer": "Cancer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b36e121c3f17ccc40c8e08", "question": "What common household object appears in the opening scene of the film \"The Sixth Sense\"?", "answer": "A light bulb", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f48", "question": "What naval hobbyist produced the landmark book \"All the World's Fighting Ships\" in 1898?", "answer": "Fred T. Jane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a899c4760d398dc9cf7a6a7", "question": "Hestia is the daughter of which two titans?", "answer": "Cronus and Rhea", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0fd", "question": "Before he escaped and returned to France, Napoleon had been exiled to what island in 1814?", "answer": "Elba", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133926e", "question": "How tall is the Academy Award statue?", "answer": "13.5 inches", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1bf", "question": "What year did Ferdinand Porsche and his team started to design the VW Beetle?", "answer": "1934", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ace9", "question": "What Harvard dropout held 535 US patents upon his death in 1991, second only to Thomas Edison?", "answer": "Edwin Land", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ad", "question": "Samhainophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Halloween", "category": "science"}, {"id": "591c3845815febcc896f927d", "question": "What is the first sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Aries", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e8a8a26404ad935a7e1a642", "question": "In what country was Shakira born?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c02c", "question": "What does Amoco stand for?", "answer": "American Oil Company", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab979f86faa38a764be52a", "question": "What is the Wankel engine typically referred to as?", "answer": "Rotary engine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339693", "question": "Who played the role of Catwoman in the 1992 movie \"Batman Returns\"?", "answer": "Michelle Pfeiffer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66c16a5bfecdd737e088e", "question": "The name for PEZ candy came from the German word for what?", "answer": "Peppermint", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6bf", "question": "What acid gives vinegar its smell and taste?", "answer": "Acetic acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe65872ae7e414034b5aef0", "question": "In what year did Alexander the Great conquer Egypt?", "answer": "332 B.C.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8efd501dd7bf43be5e7f4", "question": "What animal is said to produce the world's most expensive cheese?", "answer": "Donkey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f9f4648af848b908361b875", "question": "Should the cream or jam be spread first, if you are to use the \"Cornish method\"?", "answer": "Jam then cream", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c52a", "question": "What is both a type of bed and a layer of the rainforest?", "answer": "Canopy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4bc649076251badbeac8", "question": "What was U.S. President Woodrow Wilson's reelection campaign slogan in 1916?", "answer": "\"He Kept Us Out of War\" -- Despite the slogan, he asked Congress to declare war in 1917.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a0f", "question": "Who is the richest character in \"The Wind in the Willows\"?", "answer": "Mr. Toad", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b692", "question": "Klaxon horns were used on what type of vehicle during World War II?", "answer": "Submarines", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c924", "question": "What are a group of magpies called?", "answer": "A tittering", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4d5", "question": "How many arms does a typical snowflake have?", "answer": "Six", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a047", "question": "What song was Hawaiin Don Ho most known for?", "answer": "Tiny Bubbles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac50", "question": "The earliest evidence of the wheelbarrow was found in which country?", "answer": "China", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b9", "question": "What was Peter Gunn's girlfriend's name?", "answer": "Edie Hart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d05", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Baba Looey?", "answer": "Quick Draw McGraw", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071cb03745b36be73039cf", "question": "In what present-day country was the first space launch facility located?", "answer": "Kazakhstan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59bb2a7cc9bff04efae6d760", "question": "From which country did the US buy the United States Virgin Islands in 1916?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b03", "question": "Which character killed Elizabeth Vladimir Lensky?", "answer": "Eugene Onegin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6007805bbd51d85e222ab644", "question": "What group rebelled against the limitations of Impressionism?", "answer": "The\u00a0Post-Impressionists\u00a0rebelled against the Impressionists' naturalistic depiction of light and color.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0a2", "question": "Which player won her last tennis Grand Slam Tournament in Paris in 1999?", "answer": "Steffi Graf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0cf", "question": "The berries of the juniper tree are used to flavour which alcoholic drink?\u00a0", "answer": "Gin\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff5172bff04d658268c92f9", "question": "What food did Ancient Egyptians use as a wound disinfectant?", "answer": "Moldy bread -- Egypt was onto something, because centuries later, penicillin would be derived from the Penicillium fungi.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a87e", "question": "What country was called the Gold Coast prior to its 1957 independence?", "answer": "Ghana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d3", "question": "Which company introduced Comet cleanser back in 1956?", "answer": "Procter & Gamble", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e30", "question": "Who is Jason Schwartzman's mother?", "answer": "Talia Shire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a597", "question": "What do folks from Louisiana and Mississippi call sluggish creeks and marshy lakes?", "answer": "Bayous", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d00", "question": "What letter accounts for one of every eight used in written English?", "answer": "E", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb1", "question": "Which ingredient provides the red color in a Tequila Sunrise?", "answer": "Grenadine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a8c", "question": "Which \"Batman\" movie co-starred Nicole Kidman as Dr. Chase Meridian?", "answer": "Batman Forever", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b884", "question": "In sports, what does LPGA stand for?", "answer": "Ladies Professional Golf Association", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aad7", "question": "Which river is dammed by the Hoover Dam?", "answer": "Colorado River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa3cf7c73aa70ea0b70af1", "question": "Where will you find the Beagle Channel?", "answer": "In Tierra del Fuego Archipelago on the southern tip of South America between Chile and Argentina.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59220369a4edfd43a087ade2", "question": "Marzipan is made of which ground nut?", "answer": "Almond", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca42", "question": "Which vital organ does the adjective renal refer to?\u00a0", "answer": "Kidney\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4c8e49076251badbead7", "question": "What was the name of the space capsule that carried the first woman in space?", "answer": "Vostok 6 -- It carried Soviet cosmonaut Valentina Tereshkova in space on 1963.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd2e", "question": "What company bought naming rights to the Florida Suncoast Dome in 1996?", "answer": "Tropicana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339745", "question": "What is another name for an Academy Award?", "answer": "Oscar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cdb", "question": "What newspaper does Peter Parker work for in the \"Spider-Man\" comics?", "answer": "The Daily Bugle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acd5", "question": "Who was \"The Wizard of Menlo Park\"?", "answer": "Thomas Edison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600f6e4da9e54d890926f6c4", "question": "Where was the first Broadway theater in New York City?", "answer": "Financial District (Broadway's history began in a 280-person theater on Nassau Street in the Financial District.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b587", "question": "When was Gatorade first introduced?", "answer": "1965", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bab7", "question": "On Mount Rushmore, which one of the presidents is wearing a jacket?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a51f", "question": "What are the four largest islands of Japan?", "answer": "Honshu, Kyushu, Shikoku, Hokkaido", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59523e7e736d4be723796b50", "question": "What are the names of the \"Trailer Park Boys\"?", "answer": "Ricky, Julian and Bubbles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba58", "question": "What comedian provided the voice for the AFLAC duck in TV commercials until he was let go?", "answer": "Gilbert Gottfried", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b19e", "question": "What year did the construction of the Berlin Wall start?", "answer": "1961", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cf6", "question": "In which movie did Billie Burke portray a witch?", "answer": "The Wizard of Oz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd6bbe347d002c297e4bc", "question": "Morten Harket is the lead singer of which band?", "answer": "A-ha", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5cb70db4f96e155acab35d34", "question": "What is the national animal of Scotland?", "answer": "Unicorn", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c26", "question": "Michael Jackson was called the King of what?", "answer": "Pop", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397cb", "question": "Who won an Oscar for \"Best Actress\" for her role in \"Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf\"?", "answer": "Elizabeth Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338878", "question": "What color is Nancy Drew's hair?", "answer": "Blonde", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1a2", "question": "Who said \"Too much of a good thing can be wonderful\"?", "answer": "Mae West", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9d3", "question": "In nautical terms, what does \"Stern\" mean?", "answer": "Behind", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a1a29312f2a7826b9b871d", "question": "What was the name of the first synthetic plastic ever developed?", "answer": "Bakelite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339842", "question": "Who directed the 1986 film, \"The Color of Money\"?", "answer": "Martin Scorsese", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4f8", "question": "What lizard can be 10 feet long?", "answer": "The Komodo dragon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bab4", "question": "What secret society is the oldest men's club in the world?", "answer": "Freemasons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b8d47a2b42d4a3561a9ef9", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", who did Katchoo visit when she disappeared in Canada for 2 months?", "answer": "Emma", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afbf", "question": "Who was the first British monarch to live in Buckingham Palace?", "answer": "Queen Victoria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dd1", "question": "Who are the Glimmer Twins?", "answer": "Mick Jagger and Keith Richards", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff144b6b0ee8c595b6d39b7", "question": "What is the first book in Dan Brown's \"Robert Langdon\" series?", "answer": "\"Angels and Demons\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bfe0020b668d7dfe168b5bf", "question": "Which brand of beer does Homer Simpson drink regularly?", "answer": "Duff", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ad", "question": "What nationality was Pablo Picasso?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c02f", "question": "What type of food is Fontina?", "answer": "Cheese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdc2", "question": "Artist Bono shared Time's \"Man of the Year\" honors with what other man and his wife?", "answer": "Bill Gates", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396af", "question": "What actor founded the Purple Rose Theater Company in Michigan?", "answer": "Jeff Daniels", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb68b7e83c707845b2128", "question": "What color of star has the hottest surface temperature?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7f2", "question": "What is halite more commonly called?", "answer": "Rock salt", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be8d", "question": "What measurement was derived from the rope to which a boat's \"chip log\" was tied?", "answer": "The knot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e851fe83fe1f2a824bda", "question": "What were the four humours that the ancient Greeks believed made up the body and determined illness?", "answer": "Blood, phlegm, black bile, yellow bile", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339960", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", Groundskeeper Willie comes from what country?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad19", "question": "What bird did Benjamin Franklin favor for America's national emblem?", "answer": "The turkey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a088", "question": "Who is John Michael Osbourne better known as?", "answer": "Ozzy Osbourne", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b05a", "question": "In what year did Richard Nixon resign as President of the US?", "answer": "1974", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c137", "question": "In which sport would win the Federation Cup?", "answer": "Women's tennis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ed43eccd244b1771b64500f", "question": "When a horse gallops its hooves act as almost four additional what? ", "answer": "Hearts", "category": "Science"}, {"id": "5fe69daa20565ad31a57c779", "question": "What was the longest-ruling Chinese dynasty?", "answer": "Zhou", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae3b", "question": "What did \"abolitionists\" oppose?", "answer": "Slavery", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60173fab44491cbd7c5a17b4", "question": "What general commanded the American Expeditionary Forces on the Western Front during World War I?", "answer": "John Joseph \"Black Jack\" Pershing GCB", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ae", "question": "In which movie does Audrey Hepburn play a character named Holly Golightly?", "answer": "Breakfast at Tiffany's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba1f5874c93a3298b212d", "question": "Which city is the capital of the Austrian state of Tyrol?", "answer": "Innsbruck", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59cdb01b65ff7d326b622a60", "question": "In which continent would you find the Atlas Mountains?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133916b", "question": "Who directed the movie \"Close Encounters of the Third Kind\"?", "answer": "Steven Spielberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5906835cff9c0647b50a80a6", "question": "Alec Baldwin started hosting which ABC show on June 26, 2016?", "answer": "Match Game", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a77e", "question": "In what direction does the Nile River flow?", "answer": "North", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef59cf6ce05a3942286e07", "question": "Where did the sport of curling originate?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7db", "question": "What was the first European country to ban smoking in bars?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecca88ec223966ae8f889a", "question": "In American football, the area behind the line of scrimmage is known as what?", "answer": "The backfield", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cae6", "question": "What does the term \"scramjet\" stand for?", "answer": "Supersonic Combustion Ramjet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefa48f6ce05a3942286eb4", "question": "In the television series, \"The Man from U.N.C.L.E.,\" what does U.N.C.L.E. stand for?", "answer": "United Network Command for Law Enforcement", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0dd", "question": "Checkpoint Charlie was the gate that divided the east and west portions of what city?", "answer": "Berlin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909ccb3bb53d1af658864e2", "question": "Which composer wrote the classical piece \"Messiah\"?", "answer": "George Frideric Handel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5909cdd6bb53d1af658864ed", "question": "What year marked the first appearance of Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer?", "answer": "1939", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e2", "question": "What was the maximum number of characters that one can use in a Twitter tweet before they were doubled in 2017?", "answer": "140", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c51e", "question": "What was the name of the first space-ready shuttle?", "answer": "Columbia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c30d", "question": "What flowers are known as \"mums\"?", "answer": "Chrysanthemums", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339393", "question": "In how many Superman movies did Gene Hackman appear as Lex Luthor?", "answer": "Three", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c957", "question": "Approximately how many miles is an Astronomical Unit?", "answer": "93 million", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c3e97cfebfabb9c85d8a966", "question": "What TV show has the character Michael Stivic?", "answer": "All in the Family", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339607", "question": "Who played the role of the fugitive in the 1993 movie by the same name?", "answer": "Harrison Ford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a87d", "question": "In what city would you find the most famous street named \"Reeperbahn\"?", "answer": "Hamburg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7d0", "question": "What is a turkey stuffed with a duck stuffed with a chicken called?", "answer": "Turducken", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ab", "question": "Kansas City is built at the confluence of what two rivers?", "answer": "Kansas River and Missouri River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399e8", "question": "In the movie \"Raising Arizona\", what brand of diapers does Nicolas Cage steal from the convenience store?", "answer": "Huggies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb4c", "question": "What sign are you if you were born on Valentine\u2019s Day?", "answer": "Aquarius", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6aa4f20565ad31a57c815", "question": "The Anaconda Plan was associated to which war?", "answer": "The American Civil War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febaa287e83c707845b20dc", "question": "What does the ozone layer protect the Earth against?", "answer": "Ultraviolet light", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339897", "question": "What classic movie starred Vivien Leigh and Scarlett O'Hara?", "answer": "Gone With the Wind", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2de", "question": "What year did actor Stan Laurel die?", "answer": "1965", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c856", "question": "What zone of radiation was first detected by \"Explorer\", the first US satellite?", "answer": "The Van Allen belt", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c177", "question": "What does \"per capita\" literally mean?", "answer": "Per head", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071e773745b36be73039e3", "question": "What year saw the release of issue #1 of the \"Revival\" comic book series?", "answer": "2012", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b1e", "question": "Who wrote the book \"The Wonderful Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "L. Frank Baum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60173af844491cbd7c5a179d", "question": "What phenomenon destroyed many paintings by prehistoric people?", "answer": "Erosion -- Many cliff faces used to be adorned with ancient art, but years of erosion caused their work to be lost.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339715", "question": "Who took over as lead guitarist of the Yardbirds when Eric Clapton quit?", "answer": "Jeff Beck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4d983708b8581f80b092ae", "question": "What game won the Game of the Year award at The Game Awards 2017?", "answer": "The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b10c", "question": "In what year did both the Titanic sink and Fenway Park in Boston opened?", "answer": "1912", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133941d", "question": "What album was the first to have all of its tracks licensed for use in movies, TV shows and commercials?", "answer": "\"Play\" by Moby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4a5b49076251badbeab4", "question": "Six Flags, the famous Texas amusement park, was named after what?", "answer": "The six governments that have ruled Texas -- Specifically, France, Spain, Mexico, the Confederacy, Texas and the U.S.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d6d", "question": "Who played the role of TV's E. L. Turner?", "answer": "Ben Vereen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ea", "question": "Which Hollywood film studio's logo is a mountain surrounded by 22 stars?", "answer": "Paramount", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a720", "question": "Which city is home to the South-of-Market district?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59774295284458f1d7854421", "question": "What contestant-based reality television series aired in the United States originated in Holland?", "answer": "The Voice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590681c6ff9c0647b50a8097", "question": "Under what name did Nintendo re-release the Nintendo Entertainment System in 2016?", "answer": "Nintendo Entertainment System: NES Classic Edition", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339550", "question": "Who was Gordon Shumway?", "answer": "Alf", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cc48877e98cb97778a21", "question": "What country uses the gourde as its currency?", "answer": "Haiti", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c973", "question": "What's the largest artery in the human body?", "answer": "The aorta\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a558", "question": "What is the capital of Washington?", "answer": "Olympia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af92", "question": "What song was originally called \"Defense of Fort M'Henry\"?", "answer": "The Star-Spangled Banner", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e80629de59ea584496feae", "question": "What is the winter counterpart to Aestivation?", "answer": "Hibernation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c77a", "question": "What large reptile was popularized by Steve Irwin and Paul Hogan?", "answer": "The crocodile", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5cefc0c4948005ec986edcdf", "question": "Who is the sixth member of the group LOONA to debut?", "answer": "Kim Lip", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1af", "question": "Which singer played \"Breathless Mahoney\" in the 1990 film \"Dick Tracy\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea824fff048f679a45ac20", "question": "What color is second from the top in a rainbow?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c11", "question": "According to Exodus, what is the ninth plague of Egypt?", "answer": "Darkness", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ecaeb8c790ded87bb38fd8f", "question": "Which major motion film marks Bob Saget's directorial debut?", "answer": "Dirty Work", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c072", "question": "What is the Shaddock a variety of?\u00a0", "answer": "Citrus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf08", "question": "What crime has a person committed if they have been convicted of Regicide?", "answer": "They have killed the King", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe937b56bd93ce3a4e5f674", "question": "Ephebiphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Teenagers", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6e6", "question": "What two states share a border with Florida?", "answer": "Alabama and Georgia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f33", "question": "Which band member of Red Hot Chili Peppers died of drug overdose?", "answer": "Hillel Slovak", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e60", "question": "What word comes from the capital in Hell in Milton's \"Paradise Lost\"?", "answer": "Pandemonium", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6e5", "question": "What French scientist discovered that many diseases are caused by germs?", "answer": "Louis Pasteur", "category": "science"}]